# **AHMAD TAY**

## Researcher in Artificial Intelligence/ Data Scientist

Research scientist with critical thinking skills and five years of experience in predictive modeling, data processing, and data mining algorithms, I am currently looking for a new professional opportunity.

② ahmaddtay90@gmail.com☑ Researchgate

**\( (+33) 667768996** 

Plouzané, France

¶ GoogleScholar



## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Postdoctoral Researcher

**IMT Atlantique** 

Cct. 2022 - present

**♀** Brest, France

- Resrearcher at Laboratoire des Sciences et Techniques de l'information de la Communication et de la Connaissance (Lab-STICC (UMR CNRS 6825)- équipe RAMBO and at SMART MACADAM
- Automatic recognition of environmental noises corresponding to daily human activities
- Extracting acoustic and linguistic indicators from human speech (NLP)
- Developing a diagnostic algorithm using these metrics
- Applications in the field of neurodegenerative diseases

#### Research and Teaching Associate

**INSA** 

🗎 Sep. 2020 - Août 2022

Rouen, France

- Researcher at laboratoire d'Informatique, de Traitement de l'Information et des Systèmes (LITIS, EA 4108)
  - Leading a new project in partnership with the SCRADH (Syndicat du Centre Régional d'Application et de Démonstration Horticole)
  - · Data cleaning, pre-processing and mining
  - Development and implementation of predictive models
  - Applications in the agricultural sector
- Teaching courses in Machine and Deep Learning (Master of Science: Data Science Expert-ESD), Signal Processing, and Programming (Master: Data Science and Engineering-SID)

#### **Doctoral Researcher**

Université de Toulon - LIS (UMR 7020)

m Déc. 2017 - Juil 2021

♥ Toulon, France

- Developing of a decision support system in partnership with SCRADH-Hyères
- Implementing soft computing techniques; fuzzy logic, neural networks, and neuro-fuzzy approaches
- Generating a confidence index to measure the reliability of a predicted value
- Creating a graphical interface under Simulink for continuous monitoring purposes

## **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Automatic Control, Artificial Intelligence Université de Toulon

Master in Biostatistics

Lebanese University

**#** 2015

Beirut, Lebanon

**Bachelor** in Statistics

Lebanese University

**#** 2013

**♀** Beirut, Lebanon

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Mathematics & Statistics**

- Inferential, Descriptive, and Bayesian Statistics
- Linear Algebra
- Optimization
- Time Series

## **Artificial Intelligence**

- Machine learning:
  - Classification: Naive Bayes, SVM, Decision trees, KNN, etc.
  - Clustering: probabilistic, hierarchical and non hierarchical
  - Regression: multiple, ridge, lasso and logistic
  - Dimensionality reduction: linear and non-linear (PCA, t-SNE)
- Deep Learning: DNN, CNN, RNN, AE
- Signal processing: Kalman filter, CUSUM, correlation, convolution, windowing, sampling, reconstruction

#### **Software**

- Programming: Python (Pandas, Numpy, Keras, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, etc), Matlab & Simulink, Octave, R, C, LTFX
- Databases : SQL server
- Operating Systems : Windows, Linux

#### Communication

English: FluentFrench: AdvancedArabic: Native

## **HUMAN QUALITIES**

- · Team spirit, autonomous, persevering
- Interpersonal skills, problem solving

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Machine Learning, Stanford University, 2022
- Data Science Summer School DS3, l'École Polytéchnique X, 2019

## **HOBBIES**

· Sailing, Reading, Sport